So one of the skills of an IT system engineer or an IT system administrator is to actually
troubleshoot Windows operating system as your Windows server or your client devices.
So let's say for example, this device has an audio issue, where you can see that the audio
is not running.
And for example, you see that the audio service, there's no audio device is installed.
So if I go to my start menu and enter troubleshoot, I'm going to go to the troubleshoot settings.
So the troubleshoot settings are actually an imbued tool which you can't probably use to detect
and fix Windows operating system issues.
For example, let me just click order troubleshoot as.
Here for example, you can see we have play audio, that's moment, let me just try to run.
So what is going to do is going to try to detect the problem and see if it's like, if it's
going to actually fix that problem or not.
So you try to check, you can see check in audio device driver and do the check the driver and
there if possible check if the service have started or not or check if the driver was
properly installed or if there's an error in the driver.
So you actually check and then give you some options to actually try to fix that problem
yourself or try to fix that issue yourself, you can see it's coming for hardware changes.
So let us wait for some seconds and see what which error we see we are going to receive
or which other suggestions we are going to receive.
Okay, nice.
You after which you could not identify the problem, let's view the details and see what
it says.
Here we go.
It says, check your audio device, it's actually detected, your PC module is started,
it should not present and then if I scroll down, you can see the virtual issue is suggested,
your PC module is started, hardware changes might not have been detected.
So if we click the details here, you can also have some details information.
For example, it says, the final content that it is stored in registry for all installed
audio device, file name, we can actually click here to go to the registry log.
Also, if, for example, let's say you have an issue with your network adapter, you can
decide to just click wrong and then it's tried, you also did that and see, you can see
it says, which of, if you are not sure, select the last option and the list, so you can
select one of this option, but let just click on all network adapters and then click
next, here we go, you can see it says, it's trying to actually collect the results for
the problem that has been detected, when network adapter is actually working, what you
can see during the start of the, try to detect the issue, we have two adapters.
So let's see, which result it is going to give us, here we go, you can see, we can
decide to go to a few details information, see the details, let's see what we have, here
we have some network diagnostic log, we can't really go to the log and see what's error
message we had already detected, it says, all that networking configuration logs, we can
actually go to the network configuration.com and then on that publisher details, you can
see we have a package version and also a fan of fix, probably with wireless and all that
network adapters. So let's add also what the fuel info you get when you try to actually
fix the problem, but most of the time if, for example, there's an issue that we, without
if it's a printer or audio or power or shelf or that, you try to see if it can fix it
itself, if not, it will give you some other suggestion. So this is actually a very, very
good tool to use in your Windows operating system, we can actually be using Windows Server,
those 10 and Windows 11.